galeriasavaria.hu 2019-04-12

# Privacy Policy | Galeria Savaria online antique marketplace - Buy or sell antique, vintage items and artworks

_We are happy to provide our Privacy Policy in your language of choice, but please note that the use of  _[galeriasavaria.hu](http://galeriasavaria.hu/)  _is governed by the Hungarian version. You can view the source text by changing the language._

Protecting your data is of paramount importance to Galeria Savaria. This statement introduces the data management practice of galeriasavaria.hu (hereinafter referred to as: the “Website”) and of the other services provided by Galeria Savaria. We refer to the Website and the other services as the “Service”, as a collective name.

The data controller is Galeria Savaria LLC (113 Cherry St #94313, Seattle, WA 98104, USA, hereinafter referred to as: the “Galeria Savaria”, “Service Provider”, “Data Controller”, “we” and its inflected forms).

### **1\. Acceptance of the Privacy Policy**

We need certain information and data to operate our business and provide our services. By accepting the Privacy Policy, you reassure us that you have read and understood how we process, collect and use your data.

If you do not agree with our Privacy Policy, please do not use our services.

### **2\. What kind of information do we collect?**

When using the Service, we may collect or request data in various ways. You may decide to share certain information, but we may also request you to provide details that are essential to use the Service.

_Registration and account data:_ During a basic-level registration, you have to provide your name, or, if necessary, a company name, e-mail address and username. Depending on which of our services you use, we ask you to provide additional information, such as your residential address and telephone number. If you use our services as a seller, you have to provide your billing information (e.g.: billing name, billing address) and payment information (bank account number or bank card details or PayPal ID). In some cases, in order to safeguard the security of our Service, we may request documents that are suitable for verifying your identity, residential address and billing information. We handle these documents confidentially and they will be deleted after completing the verification.

_Profile:_ When using our services, you can provide additional information, such as a profile picture and a brief introduction. These information is made up of publicly available data. In addition to this, the following information can be seen by anyone: your username, date you joined, last time you logged in, the ratings written by others in connection with you, or the information you choose to make public.

_Automatically collected information:_ Even if you are not a registered member of the Website, we may collect information about you when using the Service. This can be, for example, an IP address, a unique device ID, cookie data, referrer information, the date and time of your visit, the device, program or browser used, the type of the operating system of the device, its version number and language settings. We can also collect information about the clicks, the websites visited, the searches and other activities performed on the site. We can aggregate activities performed and data collected from the various computers and devices. 

We use these data to prevent abuses, to maintain the secure operation of our Service, to analyse and understand how the Service works for our members and visitors, to display customized ads and provide a personalized user experience to you. For more information, please see our Cookie Policy.

_Location information:_ We may also get information on your geographic location on the basis of your IP address, or if you enable it by the device. We may use this information to customize the Service, to make region-specific settings, to adjust the content of the Website, if necessary, or to optimize our marketing activities.

_Communication with Members and the Website:_ During the communication with the Website or conducted on the Website, we may also collect shared information. This is done to prevent abuses, to protect our community and to maintain the reliability of the Website.

_Non-member information:_ Persons who are not yet a registered users of the Website may also share personal information with us. For example, when signing up for a newsletter or contacting our customer service, the visitor provides their name and e-mail address. These data are required to satisfy the visitor’s request, such as sending a newsletter or receiving a customer service reply.

_Other information:_ You can share additional information with us when you complete a form, update or add further details to your account information, respond to questionnaires, send us feedback or participate in promotions and prize winning games.

_Information originating from third parties:_ We may also collect information that others have provided about you when using the Service. We may use information learned from other sources and aggregate them with the data we have collected. The Service Provider is not liable for third party data management policies, third parties can provide information about their own privacy practices.

### **3\. Information uses, sharing and disclosure**

Data collected about you may be used for different purposes. We rely on more legal bases when using your data:

  * _Compliance with the contract and provision of services:_ We may need your personal information to comply with the contract concluded by and between us, and to provide you with our services.
  * _Consent:_ We may request your consent to the use of your personal information for example, to be able to use them for marketing purposes. You can withdraw your consent at any time.
  * _Justified cases:_ In justified cases, we may use your personal information, for example, to improve and develop the operation of our services and to ensure that you can meet the most useful content possible at our websites, e-mail notifications and newsletters. Furthermore, we may use your personal information also for administrative or legal reasons.

_Providing and improving our services:_ We may use your personal information for the purposes of analysis. This is to improve and develop our services and to enforce our legitimate interest in understanding how our Services are used. The acquired knowledge can be used to correct any mistakes and to increase the efficiency of our Services, including also tailoring our website to your individual needs.

_Create and maintain a secure and reliable service:_ We may use your data in our efforts to prevent fraud and other illegal activities. The reason for this is that we would like to provide a reliable and secure platform for our community.

We may use the data available to us for authentication, verification, billing and payment purposes, or to arrange targeted online and offline marketing activities. Furthermore, we may use the information to settle any dispute with Galeria Savaria or a member of the community. Considering your activity on the Website, we can learn about your personal preferences and we may offer you products that may be of your interest, in which we have a legitimate interest. For similar reasons, we or our sellers may run ads promoting our Services or the products of our sellers at various platforms, including also the advertising systems of Facebook and Google.

_Purchase and sale:_ As a part of the transaction, certain information must be shared with the users involved in the transaction. Shared information may include, inter alia, the name, e-mail address, telephone number of the parties, the shipping address of the buyer - except if the buyer chooses local pickup to receive the item, furthermore, the payment information of the seller (e.g.: bank account number or PayPal ID). As this process is an important part of our Service, we must do this to fulfil our obligations under the Terms and Conditions of Use. This information only serves for the arrangement of purchase and sale transactions concluded at Galeria Savaria. The Service Provider does not grant any permission to use this information to distribute unsolicited ads or to arrange purchase and sale transactions concluded outside Galeria Savaria. Without the express consent of the given person, it is forbidden to add him or her to any mail list or store or use their personal data.  
If the seller fails to solve an issue related to a problematic transaction, at its sole discretion Galeria Savaria may share the seller’s further contact details with the buyer in a justified case, including the seller’s address in order to allow the buyer to enforce their claims legally.  

_Legal and security:_ In addition to this, in certain cases, we may need your data to handle and resolve legal disputes. These may be, for example, legal disputes, inspections conducted by statutory and regulatory bodies, or efforts to enforce the Terms and Conditions of Use of the Website. We may share your data with law enforcement bodies, if it is required by the law for the prevention or detection of certain crimes and fraud, or to conduct criminal proceedings. This is done exclusively to the extent inevitably necessary to achieve the purpose of the inquiry. In order to protect our rights and property, furthermore, the rights and property of our business partners, we may share additional personal information with the authorities with the appropriate power, or if we find the activities that can be linked to a given user suspicious or infringing, or if the user shows a conduct that may be regarded as implication, furthermore, if the activities of the user violate the policies related to the use of the Service.

_Business partners:_ Galeria Savaria may also work with business partners, to facilitate or improve the functioning of our Service. These partners may offer products and services to you, which you can decide to use. This may also mean that their services are embedded into our Services or that the system of Galeria Savaria is embedded into the website and / or applications of these partners. When you use a service provided by one of our business partners, depending on the service we will have to transfer some of your data to the business partner, but only to the extent necessary to perform the service. When you are using a service of a business partner, please also read the privacy policy of the business partner, as well, to learn about how your information is handled.

Galeria Savaria is in connection with the followings business partners:

  * Pannon Parcel Service Szolgáltató Kft. - Name, e-mail address, phone number, address of the sender and recipient. The purpose of the data handling is providing courier service.

_Service providers:_ Galeria Savaria may also work with other service providers to help facilitate the operation and improvement of our Service. These may include, for example, payment service providers and other financial institutions, customer service systems or partners dealing with research, analytics and security measures. The third parties will have limited access to your data and can only use them to secure the provision of their service. In certain cases, we need to work with these service providers as they can accomplish important tasks, such as payment and delivery functions or the provision of customer service interface. In other cases, cooperation is justified because they help our work to improve our Service, for example, by analysing how we can better serve the interests of our users. In this latter case, we have a legitimate interest in working with partners who can contribute to the improvement of our Services.

Galeria Savaria is in connection with the followings business partners:

  * Customer service system: Zendesk Inc.
  * Payment service providers: Stripe Inc., PayPal Inc.
  * SMS authentication: Twilio Inc., Bip Communications Kft.
  * Server service providers: Hetzner GmbH, OVH Hosting LTD, Vultr Holdings Corporation, Amazon Web Services, Inc.
  * Analytical, advertising networks: please have a look at our Cookie Policy.

_Aggregated information:_ We may share aggregated data with our partners. In doing so, we aggregate data from our users so that they are no longer suitable for identifying our users. These are used for demographic analyses, marketing, advertising and other business purposes.

_Reorganization:_ In case of reorganization, acquisition or merger, all data available to us may be passed on to the third party. This may be necessary and may be of our legitimate interest when bringing long-term decisions on the operation of the Service. In such a case, we will notify you in advance by e-mail or on the interface of the Service, before your data become disclosed to a third party and subject to other privacy policies.

_Third parties:_ Third party extensions may also collect data about how you use our Services, such as the “share” function provided by the social networking sites that can store cookies in your browser. These activities are subject to the privacy policy of the third-party site. Furthermore, we may use cookies provided by a third party or similar technologies also for marketing purposes. These technologies make it possible to recognize a computer or device while using the Service. Please note that when you use the services of a third party, your data will be used in accordance with the privacy policy of that given third party. In such a case, to any question concerning the use of your data, the third party may give proper information. These activities serve our legitimate interest in pursuing marketing activities that can be used to offer you products and services that may be of your interest. Please note that you may request the prohibition of using your data for such purposes at any time by modifying cookie settings. For more information on this, please see our Cookie Policy.

This privacy policy does not cover the activities of third parties that are not owned or controlled by the Service Provider or the activities of persons who are not employed or controlled by the Service Provider. Galeria Savaria is not liable for these privacy and security practices and cannot be held liable for them. We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy of these service providers.

### **4\. Communication**

Galeria Savaria may contact you from time to time. We deliver these messages to you primarily by e-mail, therefore it is required to have an up-to-date e-mail address in your account through which we can get into touch with you. If you have given your consent to it, we may contact you also through other communication channels (telephone, SMS, mail) to provide customer service assistance or to offer you products, services or functions that may be of your interest.

In certain cases, we will send important notices to you about our Services. For example, such a notification can be a welcome e-mail during the registration, or the notifications in which we inform you that you have received a message or offer, somebody has purchased from you or if you as a seller has an invoice payment obligation, or if we have modified the functionality of our Service that may affect you. Depending on the importance of the content, in particularly justified cases (e.g. outstanding account debt), we may also send such notifications in an SMS.  As the knowledge of this information is essential for the intended use of the Service, you will not be able to unsubscribe from these notifications. If you would not like to receive such notifications in the future, you have the option to close your account.

When you register at our Website or sign up for a newsletter, we inform you and ask for your consent to be able to send you marketing messages from time to time. You can unsubscribe from such messages at any time, by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the message. Furthermore, our users can control these settings also by logging in to their account.

### **5\. Safety**

Protecting your personal information is important to us. We follow security requirements complying with industry-specific standards to protect your personal information. However, unfortunately, there is no way of transmitting data or storing data that would provide 100% security. So while we strive to protect your data, we cannot guarantee their absolute security. Your user account is password protected. It is particularly important to choose a password by which you can prevent any unauthorized persons from accessing your account, and to keep the password and your computer or device safe, e.g. by logging out of your account after you have completed the use of the Service.

### **6\. Your rights**

_Use of personal information:_ If you want to review, manage or modify your personal information, you can do so by signing into your account. You are responsible for keeping this information up-to-date. For security or technical reasons, you may not be able to modify some of your data. You can request their modification or update from us at any time by contacting our customer service. In certain cases, you may request a machine readable copy of your personal information stored by us.

_Data retention:_ Galeria Savaria keeps your data as long as they are required to comply with our privacy policy, to provide our Service, or until you request your personal information to be removed. If you would not like to use our Service any more in the future, you can close your account. This feature is available to you after signing into your account. We keep and use your personal data to the extent that is required by our legitimate business interests, e.g.: to detect or prevent any fraud, to enhance security and settle disputes. Furthermore, we can retain and use your data to the extent by which we can meet our legal obligations. Please note that closing of the account will not free up your username, e-mail address so that they cannot be used for a new registration. We will keep certain information (e.g.: ratings, messages, other public posts, log data), but data suitable for identification will be removed (e.g. the username). In order to prevent our Service from data loss occurred due to accidental or malicious intervention, copies of your personal data will also be retained for a certain period of time.

### **7\. Your liability**

If you use our Services, you may obtain personal information while talking to others or performing a purchase and sale transaction. For example, as a seller, you can learn the name, e-mail address, telephone number and shipping address of the buyer. You are liable for handling these data in accordance with the privacy regulations while using the Service. If you disclose the data of a person without their consent, either intentionally or through neglectful treatment of the data, so that they become available to foreign persons, you will be solely liable for disclosing the information. For example, when someone purchases an item from you, in some cases you may learn the e-mail address or other personal data of the buyer. This information may only be used for arranging the purchase and sale transaction concluded at Galeria Savaria. You may not use this information to distribute unsolicited ads or to arrange purchase and sale transactions concluded outside Galeria Savaria. Without the express consent of the given person, it is forbidden to add him or her to any mail list or store or use their personal data.  
If you and Galeria Savaria are considered to be a common data controller for certain personal data, and if Galeria Savaria is sued or obliged to pay a fine due to an act that has been committed by you as a joint data controller, you agree to fully compensate Galeria Savaria.

### **8\. Withdrawing consent**

In some cases, you can limit the way in which we use your personal information, or you can withdraw your consent by logging into your account or by contacting our customer service, specifying which consent you want to withdraw. Please note that the withdrawal of the consent does not affect the legality of the pre-withdrawal activities. After withdrawing the consent, we will not use your personal information for these purposes, unless it is our statutory obligation or required for legal reasons. Where we use your data for marketing purposes, using the unsubscribe function or by changing your account settings in your account, or by contacting our customer service, you can withdraw your consent at any time. You can also withdraw your consent by closing your user account, that automatically launches the deletion of your personal information. We do not delete the information we are required to retain.

Please note that closing your account can be started if:

  * at least 30 days have elapsed since your last transaction conducted at Galeria Savaria 
  * you do not have any transaction awaiting rating or to be completed, you do not have any pending offer, or are not participating in an active auction
  * you do not have any account debt towards Galeria Savaria
  * your username or any username related to you is not subject to any limitation, neither partially, nor fully

If any of the above cases exists, Galeria Savaria may reject the request for the closing of the account.

When closing your account please note the following:

  * By closing the account, you agree that for security reasons, for a period of 30 days, we will disable the new registrations that may be associated with the closed account.
  * We may retain certain personal information as long as it is required by our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection, prevention and security enhancement. For example, if we suspend an account for security reasons or for a violation, we need to keep certain information so that the user cannot create a new account in the future.
  * It may happen that a violation, fraud or other crime becomes revealed only after the user closes their account. Therefore, we need to keep some information, on one hand, to meet our legal obligations, and, on the other hand, to prevent a user from creating a new account. Our legitimate reason for this is to provide a reliable and secure platform for our community.
  * We do not assume any liability for the previous data or websites that have already been removed but which have still become archived by the Internet search engines. The operator of the search page should arrange their removal.

### **9.  Changes**

We may amend the Privacy Policy from time to time. We draw your attention to the important changes in one of the following ways: we display a notification when using the Service or send you a message, for example, by e-mail. We recommend that you periodically return and check for any modifications.

### **10.  Contact**

If you have any comments or suggestions regarding the Privacy Policy or the privacy practice of Galeria Savaria, please contact us by clicking on the Contact link.

* * *

### **Cookie Policy**

In order to provide you with a high-level, reliable service as smooth as possible, Galeria Savaria and its partners use cookies and similar technologies (hereinafter referred to as: the “cookie”).

If you would like to know more about what cookies are, how we use them and what options you have in connection with them, please read on.

### **What is a cookie?**

Cookie is a small data packet placed into your browser by the website and we can distinguish between 3 main types of them:

_Session cookie:_ These cookies are limited to a single visit and store information, so that you do not need to re-enter certain information while browsing the Website. Session cookies expire and become deleted shortly after leaving the Website or directly after closing the browser.

_Persistent cookie:_ These cookies store the preferences related to your visit and allow us to recognize you when you visit the Website again. They will remain in the browser until you delete them or until they expire.

_Cookies used by a third party:_ These cookies cannot be linked to Galeria Savaria and may include browsing activities across multiple websites and sessions. These can usually be ranked into the group of persistent cookies and remain in the browser until you delete them or until they expire.

Cookies store basic information about your Internet usage habits and can help to operate Galeria Savaria and customize user experience as much as possible.

### **Other cookie technologies**

In addition to cookies, we use other similar technologies, as well:

_Web beacons:_ These are small graphic elements with unique identifiers, which can be used to measure and track the actions performed on the website, together with visitor statistics. These pixels can collect information about your device, the type of the operating system, IP address, and the date and time of your visit. 

_UTM codes:_ The tracking URLs let us know from which website you have arrived to the website of Galeria Savaria.

_Social extensions:_ These are extensions run by social networks that allow you to use the services of social networking sites (such as: liking or sharing feature) by browsing a website. These social extensions may collect information about the activities performed on the website, which they can forward to the social networks.

### **How do we use cookies?**

_Security and authentication:_ We use cookies which are absolutely necessary for the operation of Galeria Savaria, as they ensure that the operation of the Service is appropriate both for the visitors and the users. For example, by maintaining security and allowing for authentication.

_Account and user preferences:_ Using cookies, we can remember your preferences, such as your language settings or your need be remembered when you visit the Website again, and we also use cookies to customize the content and appearance of the Website to suit your needs.

_Statistics and performance:_ We use cookies to collect data on the performance of the Website and to learn about the usage patterns of our visitors. These can help to discover the possible errors or we can use the knowledge obtained in this way to make the Service even more efficient. We can also better understand what pages visitors visit at Galeria Savaria, which features they use and how they use them.

_Social networks:_ Certain cookies are available to help you use the functions of social networks. Such as content sharing or other community site feature. These cookies may be stored and managed by the social network. We may also collaborate with the social sites for the purposes of analysis and marketing. You can manage your privacy settings for social networks by signing into your account registered at these websites.

_Advertisements:_ Advertising cookies ensure that the ads you see on our website and on other pages are as relevant to you as possible. These technologies provided by third parties make it possible to recognize the devices you use, and to forward demographic and interest-based information without identifying you. This way we can display customized ads. The third party service providers are not under the control of Galeria Savaria, they have their own privacy policies and practices.

### **What are my choices?**

The first time you visit our website, we remind you in a notification bar that we use cookies. By continuing to use the Service, you give your consent to their use.

You have the option to manage or disable the specific cookies. Below is a detailed description of how this works. Please note that if you delete the cookies of Galeria Savaria, it is possible that your access to certain features or sub-pages of the Website will become poor or limited.

_Browser settings:_ You can manage the cookies with your browser’s settings. The exact location of the setting depends on the type of the browser you are using. The “Help” function of your browser lets you quickly find the location of the setting. Below you will find more detailed information about how to make the settings in browsers supported by Galeria Savaria:

_Advertising networks:_ If you do not want to see interest-based ads, you can disable them by visiting [http://youronlinechoices.eu](http://youronlinechoices.eu/) or <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>. Please note that if you opt-out an online advertising network, it does not mean that you will not receive any online ads in the future or that you will not be involved in any marketing analysis. This means that the network from which you unsubscribed, will not display ads to you based on your online preferences and browsing history. Additional useful links to the settings provided by the advertising platforms used by Galeria Savaria are: [Facebook](http://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217), [Google](http://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)

You can modify your preferences on whether you would like to see personalised ads from Galeria Savaria by clicking here.

_Analysis:_ In order to better understand how the members of the community use Galeria Savaria, we may use the services of partners engaged in analysis. The services help us to enforce our legitimate interest in maintaining the reliable and safe operation of our Service, including letting us able to prevent and explore frauds.

  * Google Analytics: If you do not want Google Analytics to use your data for analysis, please [click here](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) to install the Google Analytics opt-out plugin.
  * Hotjar: If you do not want Hotjar to store your data, [click here](http://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).
  * Whos.amung.us: You can find detailed information on how to unsubscribe by clicking [here](http://whos.amung.us/legal/privacy/).
  * Matomo: You can turn off the service by using browser cookie settings.

Please note that the opt-out sites are not operated by Galeria Savaria, therefore it does not assume any liability for the access to or operation of these features.

_Mobile opt-out:_ Use the mobile device to manage browser cookie settings. Please look up the manufacturer’s manual for more detailed information.

### **Contact**

If you have any question concerning the use of cookies, you can contact us at the contact details provided in the Contact section of the Privacy Policy.
